<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Historical Archives on mlcom.org</title><link>/archives/</link><description>Recent content in Historical Archives on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Letter from a Birmingham Jail</title><link>/archives/mlk/1963-birmingham-jail-letter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/mlk/1963-birmingham-jail-letter/</guid><description>16 April 1963
My Dear Fellow Clergymen:
While confined here in the Birmingham city jail, I came across your recent statement calling my present activities &amp;ldquo;unwise and untimely.&amp;rdquo; Seldom do I pause to answer criticism of my work and ideas. If I sought to answer all the criticisms that cross my desk, my secretaries would have little time for anything other than such correspondence in the course of the day, and I would have no time for constructive work.</description></item><item><title>Letter from a Birmingham Jail</title><link>/archives/mlk/white-moderates/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/mlk/white-moderates/</guid><description>The following is an excerpt from Martin Luther King Jr.'s Letter From A Birmingham Jail. The full letter is available from our archives.
I must make two honest confessions to you, my Christian and Jewish brothers. First, I must confess that over the past few years I have been gravely disappointed with the white moderate. I have almost reached the regrettable conclusion that the Negro&amp;rsquo;s great stumbling block in his stride toward freedom is not the White Citizen&amp;rsquo;s Counciler or the Ku Klux Klanner, but the white moderate, who is more devoted to &amp;ldquo;order&amp;rdquo; than to justice; who prefers a negative peace which is the absence of tension to a positive peace which is the presence of justice; who constantly says: &amp;ldquo;I agree with you in the goal you seek, but I cannot agree with your methods of direct action&amp;rdquo;; who paternalistically believes he can set the timetable for another man&amp;rsquo;s freedom; who lives by a mythical concept of time and who constantly advises the Negro to wait for a &amp;ldquo;more convenient season.</description></item></channel></rss>