<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>mlcom.org</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter One: Commodities</title><link>/archives/marx/1867-capital-volume-one/chapter01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1867-capital-volume-one/chapter01/</guid><description>Note: Das Kapital may be considered difficult to understand the first time you review it. There is an excellent YouTube series by Dissident Theory called Understanding Marx's Capital Volumes 1-3, that does a good job at explaining the book section by section.
Section 1 THE TWO FACTORS OF A COMMODITY: USE-VALUE AND VALUE (THE SUBSTANCE OF VALUE AND THE MAGNITUDE OF VALUE) The wealth of those societies in which the capitalist mode of production prevails, presents itself as “an immense accumulation of commodities,”[1] its unit being a single commodity.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>/contribute/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/contribute/</guid><description>This website was designed to be built and maintained by the Marxist-Leninist community, not by any organization or individual. It is modeled after the open source community in this way. We hope to make the website easy to contribute to, by individuals of all backgrounds, ethnicities, nationalities, etc, but this will be an ongoing process.
The website itself is housed on GitHub.com, a popular software repository owned by Microsoft. However, it may be moved to an alternative platform in the future, if we ever encounter issues being hosted there.</description></item><item><title>Girls You Can Hit</title><link>/topics/trans-liberation/girls-you-can-hit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/topics/trans-liberation/girls-you-can-hit/</guid><description>Why Do Fascists Want To Kill Trans Women? In a nine-day period between June 25 and July 3, six Black trans women – Brayla Stone, Merci Mack, Shaki Peters, Draya McCarty, and Tatiana Hall – were found murdered. The news barely made a ripple; Black trans women and trans women of color are murdered regularly – and no one is shocked, because the gender class structure is operating as usual. Liberal-individualist analysis claims that this is simply the result of amaorphous personal &amp;ldquo;prejudices&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; that individual men, fearful of the unknown or afraid of change, attack trans women for personal reasons.</description></item></channel></rss>