<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>A Critique of The German Ideology on mlcom.org</title><link>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/</link><description>Recent content in A Critique of The German Ideology on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A. Idealism and Materialism</title><link>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/part-1-idealism-and-materialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/part-1-idealism-and-materialism/</guid><description>The Illusions of German Ideology As we hear from German ideologists, Germany has in the last few years gone through an unparalleled revolution. The decomposition of the Hegelian philosophy, which began with Strauss, has developed into a universal ferment into which all the “powers of the past” are swept. In the general chaos mighty empires have arisen only to meet with immediate doom, heroes have emerged momentarily only to be hurled back into obscurity by bolder and stronger rivals.</description></item><item><title>B. The Illusion of the Epoch</title><link>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/part-2-illusion-of-the-epoch/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/part-2-illusion-of-the-epoch/</guid><description>Civil Society and the Conception of History The form of intercourse determined by the existing productive forces at all previous historical stages, and in its turn determining these, is civil society. The latter, as is clear from what we have said above, has as its premises and basis the simple family and the multiple, the so-called tribe, the more precise determinants of this society are enumerated in our remarks above. Already here we see how this civil society is the true source and theatre of all history, and how absurd is the conception of history held hitherto, which neglects the real relationships and confines itself to high-sounding dramas of princes and states.</description></item><item><title>Preface</title><link>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/preface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1845-german-ideology/chapter01/preface/</guid><description>Hitherto men have constantly made up for themselves false conceptions about themselves, about what they are and what they ought to be. They have arranged their relationships according to their ideas of God, of normal man, etc. The phantoms of their brains have got out of their hands. They, the creators, have bowed down before their creations. Let us liberate them from the chimeras, the ideas, dogmas, imaginary beings under the yoke of which they are pining away.</description></item></channel></rss>