<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Karl Marx on mlcom.org</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/</link><description>Recent content in Karl Marx on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Marx, Karl, was born...</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/marx-was-born/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/marx-was-born/</guid><description>Marx, Karl, was born on May 5, 1818 (New Style), in the city of Trier (Rhenish Prussia). His father was a lawyer, a Jew, who in 1824 adopted Protestantism. The family was well-to-do, cultured, but not revolutionary. After graduating from a Gymnasium in Trier, Marx entered the university, first at Bonn and later in Berlin, where he read law, majoring in history and philosophy. He concluded his university course in 1841, submitting a doctoral thesis on the philosophy of Epicurus.</description></item><item><title>Marx’s Economic Doctrine</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/marxs-economic-doctrine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/marxs-economic-doctrine/</guid><description>“It is the ultimate aim of this work to lay bare the economic law of motion of modern society, i.e., capitalist, bourgeois society,”
says Marx in the preface to Capital. An investigation into the relations of production in a given, historically defined society, in their inception, development, and decline—such is the content of Marx’s economic doctrine. In capitalist society, the production of commodities is predominant, and Marx’s analysis therefore begins with an analysis of commodity.</description></item><item><title>Preface</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/preface/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/preface/</guid><description>This article on Karl Marx, which now appears in a separate printing, was written in 1913 (as far as I can remember) for the Granat Encyclopaedia. A fairly detailed bibliography of literature on Marx, mostly foreign, was appended to the article. This has been omitted in the present edition. The editor of the Encyclopaedia, for their part, have, for censorship reasons, deleted the end of the article on Marx, namely, the section dealing with his revolutionary tactics.</description></item><item><title>The Marxist Doctrine</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/the-marxist-doctrine/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/lenin/works/1914/karl-marx/the-marxist-doctrine/</guid><description>Marxism is the system of Marx’s views and teachings. Marx was the genius who continued and consummated the three main ideological currents of the 19th century, as represented by the three most advanced countries of mankind: classical German philosophy, classical English political economy, and French socialism combined with French revolutionary doctrines in general. Acknowledged even by his opponents, the remarkable consistency and integrity of Marx’s views, whose totality constitutes modern materialism and modern scientific socialism, as the theory and programme of the working-class movement in all the civilized countries of the world, make it incumbent on us to present a brief outline of his world-conception in general, prior to giving an exposition of the principal content of Marxism, namely, Marx’s economic doctrine.</description></item></channel></rss>