<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Socialism: Getting Started on mlcom.org</title><link>/topics/getting-started/</link><description>Recent content in Socialism: Getting Started on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/topics/getting-started/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Idealism vs Materialism</title><link>/topics/getting-started/idealism-vs-materialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/topics/getting-started/idealism-vs-materialism/</guid><description>All philosophies created since the advent of class society have fallen into one of two main camps: idealism or materialism.
Idealism Idealist philosophies begin with ideas and hold that these are of primary importance in shaping reality.
This means that people&amp;rsquo;s thoughts and ideas are seen as the primary factor in shaping the material world. The &amp;ldquo;law of attraction&amp;rdquo; is one such manifestation of this: it says that a person attracts the things that they think about into their life; therefore, they need only to think about the things they covet in order to &amp;ldquo;manifest&amp;rdquo; them.</description></item><item><title>Socialism: Abridged Definition</title><link>/topics/getting-started/socialism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/topics/getting-started/socialism/</guid><description>Socialism is the transitionary stage between Capitalism, and Communism. Being a transitionary stage, it inherently spans a spectrum of characteristics, being closer towards Capitalism in the earlier stages, and getting progressively closer to Communism as time goes on.
The single defining characteristic of Socialism is the inversion of the power dynamic between worker (proletariat) and capitalist (bourgeois). This is defined by Karl Marx as the Dictatorship of the Proletariat, however, dictatorship is being used differently then how you might be used to seeing.</description></item></channel></rss>