<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Critique of the Gotha Programme on mlcom.org</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/</link><description>Recent content in Critique of the Gotha Programme on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Engels to August Bebel In Zwickau</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/engels-to-bebel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/engels-to-bebel/</guid><description>London, March 18-28, 1875 Dear Bebel,
I have received your letter of February 23 and am glad to hear that you are in such good bodily health.
You ask me what we think of the unification affair. We are, unfortunately, in exactly the same boat as yourself. Neither Liebknecht nor anyone else has let us have any kind of information, and hence we too know only what is in the papers — not that there was anything in them until a week or so ago, when the draft programme appeared.</description></item><item><title>Foreword</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/foreword/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/foreword/</guid><description>The manuscript published here &amp;ndash; the covering letter to Bracke as well as the critique of the draft programme &amp;ndash; was sent in 1875, shortly before the Gotha Unity Congress, to Bracke for communication to Geib, Auer, Bebel[1], and Liebknecht and subsequent return to Marx. Since the Halle Party Congress has put the discussion of the Gotha Programme on the agenda of the Party, I think I would be guilty of suppression if I any longer withheld from publicity this important &amp;ndash; perhaps the most important &amp;ndash; document relevant to this discussion.</description></item><item><title>Marx to W. Bracke In Brunswick</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/marx-to-bracke/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/marx-to-bracke/</guid><description>London, 5 May 1875 Dear Bracke,
When you have read the following critical marginal notes on the Unity Programme, would you be so good as to send them on to Geib and Auer, Bebel and Liebknecht for examination. I am exceedingly busy and have to overstep by far the limit of work allowed me by the doctors. Hence it was anything but a “pleasure” to write such a lengthy screed. It was, however, necessary so that the steps to be taken by me later on would not be misinterpreted by our friends in the Party for whom this communication is intended.</description></item><item><title>Part I</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/part-1/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/part-1/</guid><description>1. "Labor is the source of wealth and all culture, and since useful labor is possible only in society and through society, the proceeds of labor belong undiminished with equal right to all members of society."
First part of the paragraph: &amp;ldquo;Labor is the source of all wealth and all culture.&amp;rdquo;
Labor is not the source of all wealth. Nature is just as much the source of use values (and it is surely of such that material wealth consists!</description></item><item><title>Part II</title><link>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/part-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1875-gotha-critique/part-2/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>