<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>marxism on mlcom.org</title><link>/tags/marxism/</link><description>Recent content in marxism on mlcom.org</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="/tags/marxism/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Chapter One: Commodities</title><link>/archives/marx/1867-capital-volume-one/chapter01/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/marx/1867-capital-volume-one/chapter01/</guid><description>Note: Das Kapital may be considered difficult to understand the first time you review it. There is an excellent YouTube series by Dissident Theory called Understanding Marx's Capital Volumes 1-3, that does a good job at explaining the book section by section.
Section 1 THE TWO FACTORS OF A COMMODITY: USE-VALUE AND VALUE (THE SUBSTANCE OF VALUE AND THE MAGNITUDE OF VALUE) The wealth of those societies in which the capitalist mode of production prevails, presents itself as “an immense accumulation of commodities,”[1] its unit being a single commodity.</description></item><item><title>Girls You Can Hit</title><link>/topics/trans-liberation/girls-you-can-hit/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/topics/trans-liberation/girls-you-can-hit/</guid><description>Why Do Fascists Want To Kill Trans Women? In a nine-day period between June 25 and July 3, six Black trans women – Brayla Stone, Merci Mack, Shaki Peters, Draya McCarty, and Tatiana Hall – were found murdered. The news barely made a ripple; Black trans women and trans women of color are murdered regularly – and no one is shocked, because the gender class structure is operating as usual. Liberal-individualist analysis claims that this is simply the result of amaorphous personal &amp;ldquo;prejudices&amp;rdquo; &amp;ndash; that individual men, fearful of the unknown or afraid of change, attack trans women for personal reasons.</description></item><item><title>The Three Sources and Three Component Parts of Marxism</title><link>/archives/lenin/works/1913/three-sources-and-three-component-parts-of-marxism/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>/archives/lenin/works/1913/three-sources-and-three-component-parts-of-marxism/</guid><description>This article was published in 1913 in Prosveshcheniye No. 3, dedicated to the Thirtieth Anniversary of Marx’s death.
Prosveshcheniye (Enlightenment) was a Bolshevik social, political and literary monthly published legally in St. Petersburg from December 1911 onwards. Its inauguration was proposed by Lenin to replace the Bolshevik journal Mysl (Thought), a Moscow publication banned by the tsarist government. Lenin directed the work of the journal from abroad and wrote the following articles for it: “Fundamental Problems of the Election Campaign”, “Results of the Election”, “Critical Remarks on the National Question”, “The Right of Nations to Self-Determination”, and others.</description></item></channel></rss>